<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oops on A Traveller in Space and Time</title>
    <link>http://traveller42.github.io/tags/oops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oops on A Traveller in Space and Time</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 23:57:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://traveller42.github.io/tags/oops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Twice</title>
      <link>http://traveller42.github.io/post/measure-twice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 23:57:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://traveller42.github.io/post/measure-twice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;measure-twice-cut-order-once:d8b76d1b66f429937aec64249c3d9e10&#34;&gt;Measure Twice; &lt;del&gt;Cut&lt;/del&gt; Order Once&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While assembling my portable supercomputer, I discovered that the cables I
had ordered were too short.  I had neglected to allow for the strain-reliefs
at each end and the need to not stress the sockets these cables are plugged
into.  I should have used the longer cables I have to determine the length I
needed before ordering all the cables for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Ideas</title>
      <link>http://traveller42.github.io/post/bad-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 23:59:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://traveller42.github.io/post/bad-ideas/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bad-ideas:aec35b56d95e3a3d35159fa91aa48dfb&#34;&gt;Bad Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to launch a two-years dormant VM on a current version of
VirtualBox on a 7 year old computer that is definitely showing
its age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was prompted by a change in policy by Code 42 Software, the
owners of CrashPlan, a very good backup program and service.
The new policy is to delete cloud repositories for computers that
have not connected in over 6 months.  This is only an issue as I
have a couple of Windows VMs that I keep for the rare times I need
a Windows environment.  Each of these VMs has not been active in
two years as I have had no need to run a program on Windows in that
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there are a couple resources that I would like to
maintain that require Windows.  Therefore, I decided to launch one
of the VMs and update the CrashPlan software and let it refresh the
repository.  It has now been trying to launch the VM for almost an
hour.  It has also effectively locked up the GUI for the old computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is being composed on my Chromebook where I have duplicated the
git repo for the site.  I should document the steps needed as someone
may want to do it again some day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to leave the poor system trying to run the VM.  Hopefully, I
can either log into a shell, or get control back on the GUI enough to
shutdown the VM.  I do have a good backup, so I could just move the
data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>